《法外情真》前情提要
Previously on The Guardian.
塔利克  把枪
Taliek put the gun...
我在代表塔利克·艾伦
I'm representing Taliek Allen.
上诉
in his appeal.
联邦想要剥夺塔利克·艾伦的生命
The Commonwealth wants to take Taliek Allen's life.
死亡不是随便就能发给谁的东西
Death is not something to be handed out arbitrarily.
你是在告诉我  你在拉选票解雇我儿子吗
Are you telling me that you are trying to round up enough votes to fire my son?
我今天不会改选票的
I'm not changing my vote today.
你要是把尼克投票出局了  把我也投出去吧
You vote Nick out, you vote me out as well.
现在都无所谓了
It doesn't matter now.
沃尔特  嘿  我是尼克·法林
Walter. Hey, it's Nick Fallin.
我觉得现在是时候一起坐下来谈谈工作了
l think it's time we sat down and talked about working together.
明天怎么样
How about tomorrow?
好  可以  谢谢  沃尔特  拜拜
Great. Great. Thanks, Walter. Bye.
尼克·法林
Nick Fallin.
对  是  我马上到
Right. Yeah, l'll be right there.
嘿  医生说了什么
Hey. What did the doctor say?
他想做剖腹产
He wants to preform a C-section.
为什么
Why?
孩子的心跳不规律
The baby's heartbeat's irregular.
真的有必要吗  露露  你才35周
ls it really necessary? Lulu, you're 35 weeks.
医生在担心  尼克
The doctor's concerned, Nick.
我能感受到心脏的跳动
l'm spotting and the heart rate is fluctuating,
他就是不能再等了
and he just doesn't want to wait any longer.
露露  你不用做你不想做的事
Lulu. you don't have to do anything that you don't want to do.
我知道  我知道  但是我害怕  尼克
l know, l know. But l'm scared, Nick,
我不想孩子出什么事
and l don't want anything to happen to the baby.
该走了  亲
lt's time to go, sweetheart.
你来吗
Are you coming?
嗯
Yeah.
第三季  第二十二集
法外真情
翻译  章鱼哥
校对  油 球
特效  转轮 枪
法林先生吗  我是布雷姆医生
Mr. Fallin? Dr. Brem.
你好
Nice to meet you.
我治疗过很多唐氏综合症的孩子  所以如果你有任何问题
l work with a lot of  Down Syndrome babies, so if you have any questions...
谢谢
Thank you.
我们检查了她的心脏  超声波看起来挺好的
We checked her heart. The echocardiogram looked good.
她的新生儿评分也正常  只是出生体重会有点低
Her APGARs are normal. She's just low birth weight.
所以我们会等到她五磅的时候再让她离开早产保温箱
So we'll leave her in the isolette until she gets up to five pounds.
要待多久
How long will that be?
三到四天
Three or four days.
她是个健康的女宝宝  法林先生  恭喜
She's a healthy baby girl, Mr. Fallin. Congratulations.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
她怎么样了
How is she?
很好
She's great.
有没有哭
ls she crying?
不  没有  她睡着了
No. No. She's asleep.
他们有说我什么时候能抱她了吗
When did they say that l can hold her?
医生说她三到四天就能出来了
The doctor said that she could come out in three or four days.
- 我想抱抱她  - 我知道  我知道
- l want to hold her. - l know. l know.
不  我是真的想
No, l really want to.
我知道
l know.
什么  工作上发生什么了吗
What--what happened with work?
我被解雇了
l got fired.
噢
Oh.
抱歉
l'm sorry.
我今天晚点和沃尔特·麦克尼尔有个会
l have a meeting with Walter McNeil later today.
他想让我加入他的事务所
He wants me to join his firm.
是吗
Oh?
你知道  我  你能帮我个忙吗
You know, l... Could you do me a favor?
LSP的资金申请书  我忘在我桌上了
LSP funding application. l left it on my desk.
就把它给  呃  阿尔文
Just give it to, uh, Alvin.
告诉他会议在周五
Tell him that meeting is Friday.
好的
Sure.
我真的累了
l'm really tired.
恭喜  她叫什么名字
Congratulations. What's her name?
呃  我们还没有想好
Uh, we don't really have one yet.
她  呃  她来得有点  早了
She, uh, she came kinda... early.
这很棒  你们会收获很多乐趣的
That's wonderful. You guys are gonna have so much fun.
呃  你没什么机会来这儿接案子了
Uh, you're not here by any chance to take a case or two.
不
No.
因为阿尔文在他办公室里有点自闭
Because Alvin has kind of shut himself in his office.
有点
Kind of?
他把自己关在办公室里
He has shut himself in his office,
我不知道在这里做什么
and l kind of have no idea what l'm doing here.
我在弗兰克尔法官面前要做个拘留听证会
l have this detention hearing in front of Judge Frankel.
有什么建议吗
Any advice?
弗兰克尔吗  对  直接说重点
Frankel? Yeah. Get straight to the point.
不要试着去打动他  因为他不在乎
Don't try to pull on his heartstrings because he doesn't care.
- 阿尔文  - 嘿  恭喜
- Alvin. - Hey. Congratulations.
是个女孩  很好啊
A baby girl. Terrific.
谢谢
Thanks.
露露想让我给你些提醒关于这次
Lulu wanted me to remind you about the meeting
州财政委员会的会议
with the State Funding Board.
- 脑额叶损伤  - 什么
- Frontal lobe damage. - What?
昨晚  在最高法院拒绝审理塔里克的案子后
Last night, after the Supreme Court refused to hear Taliek's case,
我回去翻遍了他的档案  想找点什么
l went back over his files looking for something, anything.
脑额叶损伤吗
Frontal lobe damage?
- 去年用卸胎棒袭击的  - 对
- The attack last year with a tire iron. - Right.
主治医生做了个大脑皮层创伤的标记
The treating doctor made a notation that there was trauma to the cerebral cortex.
他的公辩律师从没为他辩护过
His public defender never entered it into his defense.
如果有脑损伤的话就不能被处死
You can't be put to death if you have brain damage.
好吧  阿尔文  我刚告诉露露我会来的
Well, Alvin, l just told Lulu l'd stop by.
她就是想确认你没有忘记
She just wanted to make sure that you remembered
和董事会的资金会议
the meeting with the Funding Board.
你能帮我把这个资料搬到会议室吗
Would you help me move this stum into the meeting room?
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
格雷琴告诉我你回来了
Gretchen told me you were back here.
对
Yeah.
噢  你取名字了吗
Oh, do you have a name yet?
没有
No.
好吧  恭喜你  儿子
Well, congratulations, son.
谢谢
Thanks.
我听说你和麦克尼尔开会了
l heard you had a meeting with McNeil.
传得真快
Word travels fast.
那就是真的了  是吧
So it's true, huh?
对
Yeah.
麦克尼尔
McNeil.
我一直觉得他有点滑头  但
l always thought he was a little slick, but...
好吧  他挺好的  挺好的
Well, he's fine. He's fine.
听着  儿子  我有关于  呃
Listen, son, l have about, uh,
一笔三百万的生意  我可以把他过渡给你
3 million in business that l could transition over to you.
- 你要辞职了吗  - 好吧  我已经71岁了  儿子
- You're stepping down? - Well, l'm T1 years old, son.
但是合伙人怎么办
But what about the partners?
好吧  对我来说  我一点也不在乎那些合伙人
Well, as far as l'm concerned, l don't give a damn about the partners.
- 那  你需要帮忙处理这些垃圾吗  - 不  我明白了
- So, you need help with this crap? - No, l got it.
你知道  我可以找个人把你剩下的东西送过去
You know, l could get a messenger to send over the rest of your stuff.
好吧
Great.
尼克  嘿
Nick. Hey.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 露露怎么样了  - 没事
- How's Lulu doing? - Fine.
好  不错  不错
Yeah. Good. Good.
好吧  尼克  我就是
Well, gosh, Nick, l'm just...
我就是太为你高兴了  兄弟
l'm just so happy for you guys.
那  杰克  你什么时候有空
Well, Jake, when you get a moment,
把斯克拉化学的文件送到我家吧
send the Sklar Chemical file to my house.
好的  尼克  关于这个宝宝的消息真的很棒
Okay. And, Nick, it's really great news about the baby.
好  好
Great. Great.
很好
Great.
那么  呃  我们问了你很多问题
So, uh, we've asked you a lot of questions.
你有什么要给我们的吗
Do you have any for us?
没有
No.
好吧  尼克  如果你加入  我们同意
Well, Nick, if you're in, we're in.
一起干吧
Let's do it.
好极了
Great!
好的  那
Okay. Well...
欢迎加入事务所
Welcome to the firm.
谢谢
Thanks.
那么  尼克  我们明天约了约翰·克莱顿
So, Nick, we've got John Clayton coming in tomorrow.
- 我之前是他的代表  - 我知道
- l used to represent him - l know.
- 那有问题吗  - 没有
- Is that a problem? - No.
很好  你知道他的弱点
lt's great. You know his foibles.
对  我知道
Yes, l do.
我们需要一点帮助来卖他的公司  所以  如果你不介意
We need a little help selling his company. So, if you don't mind?
- 不  我不介意  - 好的
- No, l don't mind. - Good.
这会很有趣的  尼克
This is gonna be fun, Nick!
你懂的  在一起工作
You know, working together.
对  对  会很有趣
Right. Yeah. It'll be fun.
会的  没错
lt will be. Yeah.
她睡着了
She's sleeping.
孩子怎么样了
How's the baby?
所以  我有个问题
So, l got a problem.
在他们处死塔里克·艾伦之前还有十天
Taliek Allen's got ten days before they execute him.
所以我今天必须提交救济请愿书
So l have to file a petition for relief with the trial court
给初审法庭和宾州最高法院
and the Pennsylvania Supreme Court today.
祝你好运
Good luck.
加大支持的备忘录
Plus supporting memoranda.
- 那个工作量很大  - 我没法独自完成
- That's a lot of work. - l can't do it alone.
阿尔文  露露刚生了孩子  我才刚开始新的工作
Alvin, Lulu's just had a baby. l've just started a new job.
我没办法一个人做
l can't do it alone.
塔里克昨天收到他的问候信了
Taliek got his greeting's letter yesterday.
问候什么
Greetings?
来自宾州英联邦的问候
''Greetings from the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania.
您的行刑日期已经安排好了
Your execution day has been scheduled.''
这是问候吗
Greetings?
这就是说事情开始了
That's the way it starts.
你去过南美吗
You ever been to South America?
没有
No.
我曾经想过去南极洲
l've been thinking about going to Antarctica.
有什么是必须在南美做的吗
What does that have to do with South America?
你要飞到智利才能到南极
You gotta fly to Chile to get to the South Pole.
噢
Oh.
我联系了这家邮轮公司
l contacted this cruise company.
他们派了一艘船头带有破冰设备的船
They send a ship with an icebreaker on the bow.
正好直切入冰里
Just cuts right through the ice.
应该会很棒的
Supposed to be incredible.
我有些好消息
l've got good news.
你得了大脑额叶损伤
You have a frontal lobe injury.
当你受到攻击后住院的时候
When you were hospitalized after the attack,
你的一个医生说你有脑损伤
one of your doctors stated that you had brain damage.
那是什么意思
What's that mean?
意味着我们可以辩护了
lt means we have a defense,
一个你的公辩律师在你审判期间应该提出的辩护
a defense your public defender should've brought up during your trial.
噢  你可以把我从这里弄出去吗
Oh, you can get me out of here?
好吧  我想我们可以让你活下去
Well, l think we can keep you alive.
我们正在向法院提出动议  要求他们
We're filing motions with the courts asking them
考虑这个新的证据
to consider this new evidence.
我想你会说他们已经拒绝我们了
l thought you said they already rejected us.
那是他们在知道这个新证据之前
That was before they knew about this.
- 那他们现在听你说了吗  - 希望会
- And they'll hear you now? - That's the hope.
如果他们不呢
lf they don't?
那我们就不得不为特赦委员会做准备了
Then we have to prepare for the Board of  Pardons.
那是他们让人乞求活命的地方  是吗
That's where they make you beg for your life, right?
好吧  你必须写一份令人信服的声明给他们  表示你应该活着
Well, you have to write a statement convincing them that you should live.
这就是我为什么带了尼克
That's why l brought Nick.
我必须确保那些动议能被申请
l have to make sure those motions get filed.
尼克会待着在这里帮你完成你的声明
Nick's gonna stay and help you with your statement.
这是些参考
Here are the guidelines.
坚持住  塔里克
Hang in there, Taliek.
你确定不喜欢玛格丽特吗
You definitely don't like Margaret?
不确定
Not really.
你也不喜欢索菲亚吗
And you don't like Sophia?
好吧  比起玛格丽特我更喜欢它
Well, l like it better than Margaret.
你两个都不喜欢吗
You don't like either one?
我不知道
l don't know.
好吧  你有什么主意吗
Well, do you have any ideas?
我想用我母亲的名字给她起名
l'd like to name her after my mother.
你听到我说的了吗
Did you hear what l said?
你读了那个社工放下的东西了吗
Did you read that stum that the social worker dropped om?
读了
Yeah.
这个孩子需要更多的关注
This baby just needs so much attention.
我们不能随便起个名字给她
There's just no way that we can just hand her off to anyone.
我们能晚点谈这个吗
Can we talk about this later?
当然
Sure.
哇  变化很大啊
Wow, it's so different.
嘿
Hey.
好像你焕然一新了
lt's like a whole new you.
你来这儿做什么
What are you doing here?
一年五万一千美元
How does _51 ,OOO a year,
没有公司信用卡  你自己付停车费  每周按小时计费  听起来怎么样
no corporate credit cards, pay your own parking, and 70-hour weeks sound?
像扯淡
Like crap.
你想担任匹兹堡的法律负责人吗
Would you like to be head of Legal Services of Pittsburgh?
什么
What?
露露想做兼职
Lulu wants to work part-time.
- 她做兼职  - 今天早上打我电话
- She does? - Called me this morning.
告诉我可以开始找替补的人了
Told me to start looking for a replacement.
好吧  她还什么都没和我说
Well, she didn't say anything to me.
你有兴趣吗
You interested?
没有
No.
- 为什么不  - 我有工作了
- Why not? - l have a job.
这个工作吗
This?
对
Right.
这个吗
This.
对
Right.
塔里克的声明怎么样了
How's Taliek's statement going?
挺好的  不错
Fine. Fine.
好
Okay.
你需要用你自己的话阐述犯罪的细节
You need to, in your own words, state the details of the crime
来请求原谅
for which you're requesting a pardon.
他们已经知道发生什么了
They already know what happened.
对  我只是需要填满这张表  所以我需要你的话
Yeah, l'm just filling out the form. So l need your words.
我射了那些家伙
l shot those guys.
继续
Go on.
我被一根管子打了
l got beat with a pipe.
我的孩子没了
l lost my baby.
很多人都看向另一边  所以我拿起枪就追上去了
A lot a people looking the other way, so l just got my gun and went up there.
我不知道我为什么这么做  我不知道
l don't know why l did it, man, l don't.
可以了  用你的话说
All right. In your words,
为什么你相信你的请求可以得到宽恕
why do you believe that your plea for mercy should be granted?
因为我不想死
'Cause l don't want to die.
不  塔里克  那样说没用
No, Taliek, that's just not gonna work.
那我应该说什么 呵
What am l supposed to say, huh?
听着  我们为什么要做这个  我会输的
Look, why are we even doing this? l'm just gonna lose.
还没盖棺定论
You don't know that.
你知道  我会记住在最后的时刻你试着帮助过我
You know, l remember the last time you tried to help me.
你的心不在这儿  哪怕只是一点  然后我们输了
Your heart wasn't in it, not even a little, and we lost.
是的  你对它毫不在乎
Yeah, you didn't give a damn about it.
看吧  你就只是说说说
See, you just talked and talked and talked,
但是脑子里什么都没有想
but there was nothing happening behind your eyes.
用你的话来说  为什么你要请求宽恕
ln your words, why should your plea for mercy be granted?
- 你想我死吗  - 不  我不想
- You want me to die? - No, l don't.
- 为什么  - 这和我没关系  塔里克
- Why? - It's not about me, Taliek.
现在有了  因为你是要我的生命而战斗的人
lt is now, since you're the one who's gotta fight for my life.
你知道  为什么你不花点时间来想想关于宽恕的问题呢
You know, why don't you just take a little time and think about this.
听着  我没有太多时间了  你知道的  对我而言
Look, l don't have much, you know, for myself.
除了这一件事  伙计
Except for one thing, man.
那是我的骄傲
That's my pride.
所以如果你不觉得我们可以做这件事  现在就告诉我
So if you don't think we can do this thing, just tell me now,
而不是浪费你和我的时间
instead of wasting your time and mine
做一些你不想做的事
doing something you don't want to do.
说实话  你不认为我们能成功
Be honest. You don't think we can win this thing.
你有非常小的机会  好吗
You have very little chance, okay?
所以  用你的话说
So, in your words--
那又有什么意义呢  伙计  你为什么
Then what's the point, man! Why are you--
嘿  我准备走了
Hey, l'm ready to roll.
你的人说服我接受这件事
You guys talked me into taking this thing.
我是说  我想要两千七百万  而你让我接受两千四百万
l mean, l wanted 27 million, and you talked me into taking 24.
那么  我就损失了三百万  现在是这意思么  你在开玩笑吗
So, l'm out three million there. And now this? You gotta be kidding me.
按照惯例  卖方必须支付所有环境清理的费用
lt is customary for the seller to pay for any environmental clean-up.
那是两万两千美元
lt's _22,OOO.
对
Right.
买家对这个态度很坚决
The buyer's adamant about this.
那卖方也是如此
So is the seller.
打扰一下  法林先生
Excuse me. Mr. Fallin?
我很抱歉  但是有一位马斯特森先生正在等您
l am so sorry, but there's a Mr. Masterson waiting for you.
他说是生死攸关的情况
He says it's literally a life or death situation.
两分钟
Two minutes.
你同意条款  然后我这里  那些是条款
You agree to terms. And in my book, those are the terms.
我是说  一旦你同意了条款  你就不能再改了
l mean, once you've agreed to the terms, you can't just change the terms.
法院拒绝了我们的请求
The courts denied our claims.
- 他们有给任何理由吗  - 他们不需要给
- Did they give any reason? - They don't have to.
抱歉
l'm sorry.
我去找了塔里克  他把我解雇了
l went to tell Taliek. He fired me.
他说你告诉他没必要再试了
He says you told him there's no point in trying any more.
- 不  我不是这么说的  - 你到底说了什么
- No, that's not what l said. - What the hell did you say?
阿尔文  你想我试着帮那个家伙
Alvin, you wanted me to try and help the guy.
我按你说的做了
l did what you asked.
如果他炒了他的律师  然后  你知道  我们能做什么吗
lf he fires his lawyers, then, you know, what can l do?
对  好
Right. Well--
你知道  我有个会才开了一半
You know, l'm in the middle of a meeting...
好吧  现在只剩下一个赦免委员会的审讯了
Well, the thing is all that's left is a Board of Pardons hearing.
一个犯人不能自己辩护  所以如果他不用我们的话  他就要死了
A prisoner can't represent himself. So if he doesn't use us, he's dead.
但是好吧  回去开你的会吧
But please, go back to your meeting.
我告诉过那个狗娘养的菲尔普斯了  我要两千四百万  就是这样
l told that son of a bitch Phelps l would take the 24 million, but that's it.
不要在讨价还价了  我的意思很清楚了
No nickel and diming from signing to closing. And l meant it.
我不会再花一分钱了
l'm not shelling out another penny.
好吧  我会打电话给菲尔普斯
All right. l'll call Phelps,
告诉他您拒绝支付环境清理的费用
tell him you refuse to pay for the environmental clean-up.
可以
Good.
还要告诉他我不喜欢改变条款
And tell him l don't appreciate the changing terms.
生意不是这么做的
That's no way to do business.
嘿  你来这真是太好了  尼克
Hey. Really great to have you here, Nick.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
她怎么样了
How is she?
她挺好的
She's good.
她醒了两三个小时
She was wide awake for a couple of hours.
她用力捏我的手指
She squeezed my finger really hard.
那很棒
That's great.
你知道  我把我的地址本忘在我办公室的桌子上了
You know, l left my address book on my desk in my office.
你能帮我拿一下吗
Could you please get it for me?
- 当然  - 谢谢
- Sure. -Thanks.
阿尔文告诉我你不打算回去工作
Alvin told me you're not going back to work.
对  不做全职了
Yeah. Not full-time.
你什么时候决定的
When did you decide that?
昨天
Yesterday.
她需要我
She needs me.
好吧  我觉得你会做出正确的决定
Well, l think you're making the right decision.
那么  那位女士从行政办公室来的
So, the woman from the administrative office came by
带着出生证明
with the birth certificate.
我还没有填
l haven't filled it out yet.
好吧  我会帮你填的
Well, l could do that for you.
不用  我想先和你谈一下
No. l wanted to talk to you about it first.
好
Right.
我想因为我有孩子的监护权
l think that because l am gonna have physical custody
而且  因为我们没有结婚
and, uh... and because we're not married--
你想她用你的姓氏吗
You want her to have your last name?
对  我  我是这么想的  对
Yeah. l think--l think so, yeah.
好  我准备去看看她  那
Well, l'm gonna go see her, so...
- 好  - 好
- Okay. - Okay.
- 嗨  - 嘿
- Hi. - Hey.
我是这个想解放她自己的女孩的代表
l'm representing this girl who wants to emancipate herself.
- 她还没有工作吗  - 不  还没有
- Does she have a job yet? - No, not yet.
好吧  除非她有工作  否则你赢不了
Well, unless she has a job, you won't win.
南极  你什么时候去
Antarctica. When are you leaving?
我不去
l'm not.
- 为什么不去  - 我得工作
- Why not? - l have to work.
好吧  你错过了你的机会  总之
Well, you've missed your window, anyway.
- 你什么意思  - 季节
- What do you mean? - Seasons.
在赤道以南  它们的季节相反  那儿下面太冷了
South of the equator, they're the opposite. It's freezing down there.
即使你想去的话
Even if you wanted to go.
- 你的同情心在哪儿  - 什么
- Where's your compassion? - What?
你的同情心  它在哪儿
Your compassion. Where is it?
我今天就拜托了你一件事  一件事
l entrusted you to do one thing today. One thing.
帮助一个死刑犯  给他一点希望
Help a condemned man. Give him a little hope.
你做了什么
And what'd you do?
好吧  他问我他的机会是什么  阿尔文
Well, he asked me what his chances are, Alvin,
所以我决定诚实的告诉他  我告诉了他真相
so l decided to be honest with him. l told him the truth.
塔里克·艾伦  七岁时
Taliek Allen: Seven years old.
他的爸爸在塔里克看电视的时候朝自己的头开了枪
His father shoots himself in the head while Taliek is watching television.
塔里克·艾伦  十岁时  他的妈妈遗弃了他
Taliek Allen: Ten years old. His mother abandons him.
塔里克·艾伦  十一岁时  贩毒卖可卡因被捕
Taliek Allen: 1 1 years old. Arrested selling crack cocaine.
- 我知道这些故事  阿尔文  - 这些不只是故事  尼克
- l know the stories, Alvin. - These aren't just stories, Nick.
这是一段人生
This is a life.
你和我们一起多久了
How long were you with us?
有没有清醒过
Were you even awake?
尼克  嘿  布拉德·富尔顿
Nick! Hey! Brad Fulton.
呃  是  我知道
Uh, yeah, l know.
很高兴你能帮忙克莱顿的案子
Glad you're helping out in the Clayton matter.
噢  谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
约翰是我的客户  我带他来的
John's my client. l brought him in.
对
Right.
只是为了让你更明白
Just so you're real clear.
好
Great.
感谢你的帮忙
Glad you're helping out.
你和我应该  呃  有时间去喝一杯
You and l should, uh, go get a drink sometime.
噢  呃  和菲尔普斯谈克莱顿的事吗
Oh, uh, talk to Phelps on the Clayton matter?
- 还不用  - 克莱顿每小时都打电话来
- Not yet. - Clayton's calling every hour.
好吧  我去
All right. l'll get on it.
- 我知道这单只有两万两千  但是  我马上就做
- l know it's only 22 grand, but-- - l'll do it right now.
查·菲尔普斯  谢谢
Chuck Phelps, please.
查  嘿  尼克·法林
Chuck, hey. Nick Fallin.
听着  呃  我在麦克尼尔和约翰·克莱顿一起工作
Listen, uh, l'm over at McNeil working with John Clayton.
对  你知道  我打电话来是为了清理费用
Yeah. You know, l was calling about the clean-up costs.
噢  对  我完全理解
Oh, yeah, l understand perfectly.
但是  呃
But, uh...
也许我们可以各退一步
Maybe we could meet somewhere in the middle.
查克  我只是个传话人  查  查
Chuck, l'm just the messenger. Chuck--Chuck...
好  高兴  呃  跟你聊也很高兴
Yeah. Nice, uh-- Nice talking to you, too.
露露  嘿
Lulu. Hey.
你知道  我在想关于出生证明的事
You know, l was thinking about the birth certificate.
就做你特么想做的吧
Just do whatever the hell you want.
我没生气
l'm not mad.
好吧
Fine.
好  可以  拜
Yeah. All right. Bye.
杰克·斯塔克
Jake Straka.
莎拉  你知道我是谁  让他来听电话
Sarah, you know who it is. Just put him on the phone.
什么  他想让我等  想让我等他
What, he wants me to hold? He wants me to hold?
莎拉  你不用让我
Sarah, you do not put me on ho--
那么  我在第十八洞打出了三英尺的标准杆
So, l've got a three-foot put for par on the 18th hole.
如果我做到了  沙利文会欠我四百美元  但是我们就失去了一个客户
lf l make it, Sullivan owes me 400 bucks but we lose a client.
所以我试着在左边错过它
So l try and miss it to the left,
但是我推了它  那该死的球就进洞了
but l push it, and the damn ball goes in the hole.
- 我需要斯克拉的文件  - 嘿  尼克
- l need the Sklar file. - Hey, Nick.
斯克拉是我的客户  不是你的
Sklar is my client, not yours.
他们给你写了一封信  要求你转交文件
They wrote you a letter requesting you transfer the files.
所以转交这该死的文件
So transfer the damn files.
好的  尼克  我真的不想有人用这种语气和我说话
Okay, Nick. l would really appreciate not being spoken to in this tone of voice.
你就不能闭上嘴  跟我去拿我的文件吗
Will you just shut up, move and get my file?
- 嘿  伙计  - 好
- Hey, man. - Okay.
亨德森  帮你弄来的一个
Henderson. Landed that one for you.
弗里茨吗  是谁带来的  杰克
Fritz? Who brought that in the door, Jake?
看
Look--
尼古拉斯
Nicholas!
他故意留着我的文件
He's deliberately keeping my files.
他试图偷我的客户  他不回我的电话
He's trying to steal my clients. He won't return any of my calls.
所以你觉得你过来然后  然后呢
So you thought you'd come over here and--and what?
好吧  我想要回我的文件
Well, l wanted my files back.
这只是生意
lt's just business.
你也会做同样的事情
You would have done the same thing.
那  你想怎么做  呃
So... how do you, uh...
你觉得你工作的这家新事务所怎么样
How do you like this new firm you're working with?
挺好的
lt's fine.
你感觉你自己能在麦克尼尔那里长做吗
You see yourself doing business with McNeil for a long period of time?
对  希望如此
Yeah, that's the hope.
好  好
Yeah, right.
有什么问题吗
Well, what's the problem?
只是好奇你的选择
Just wondering about your choice.
- 好吧  我没有  - 你不这么想吗
- Well, l didn't really have one. - You don't think so?
- 爸  你到底想说什么  - 我就只是好奇你的选择
- Dad, what are you trying to say? - l'm just wondering about your choice.
好吧  像我说的  爸  我根本没有选择
Well, like l said, Dad, l didn't really have one.
我不能保证我们会赢
l can't promise you that we will win.
但是我可以保证我们会尽最大的努力为你辩护
But l can promise you that we will represent you to the best of our abilities.
我做不到比那更好的了
l can't do any better than that.
这个听证会两小时后开始  你要让我知道你想要我们做什么
The hearing starts in two hours. You let me know what you want us to do.
塔里克·艾伦杀了两个人
Taliek Allen killed two people.
他没有否认
He doesn't deny that.
但我们不要欺骗自己了
But let's not kid ourselves.
塔里克·艾伦也是名受害者
Taliek Allen's a victim, too.
一个不光彩的  怠惰的  既偏见又愚蠢的受害者
A victim of indimerence, of laziness, prejudice and stupidity.
迈克尔·卡什曼是匹兹堡纪念医院的医生
Dr. Michael Cashman of Pittsburgh Memorial Hospital
诊断出塔里克·艾伦在2003年11月24日患有
diagnosed Taliek Allen on November 24, 2003, with, and l quote,
严重的脑额叶损伤
''significant frontal lobe damage.''
他的脑额叶  大脑中控制他的冲动和行为的部分
His frontal lobe, the part of his brain that controls his impulses and his actions,
是有缺陷的  而他的律师从未提过这一点
is flawed, and yet his lawyer never mentioned this.
如果塔里克在审判中得到充分的辩护
Had Taliek been adequately represented at trial,
他的律师无疑会说明这个医学事实
his lawyer would have, no doubt, introduced this medical fact,
陪审团也无疑会选择不判他的死刑
and the jury would have, no doubt, chosen not to sentence him to death.
女士们先生们  你们没有选择只能宽恕他
Ladies and gentlemen, you have no choice but to grant him clemency.
塔里克·艾伦被他同伴组成的陪审团
Taliek Allen was tried by a jury of his peers,
证明残忍地杀害了两名无辜的人而被判处死刑
convicted of brutally murdering two innocent people and sentenced to death.
他上诉的每个法院都维持了这一判决
That sentence has been upheld by every court to which he has appealed.
现在有了新的事实  新的证据
There are new facts, new evidence.
这不是赦免委员会的工作
lt's not the Board of Pardons job
去考虑听取法庭拒绝的证据
to consider evidence that the courts have refused to hear.
我有证据证明塔里克·艾伦有脑损伤
l have evidence that proves that Taliek Allen has brain damage.
谢谢你  马斯特森先生  我们会对它进行表决
Thank you, Mr. Masterson. We'll put it to a vote.
不宽恕
No to clemency.
不
No.
- 不  - 不
- No. - No.
拒绝宽恕
Clemency is denied.
你们特么的怎么就能判他死刑
How the hell can you sentence somebody to death
你们甚至不知道当时他们在做什么
when you don't even know if they knew what they were doing?
你有机会发言的  马斯特森先生
You had your chance to speak, Mr. Masterson.
他得了脑损伤  他有脑损伤
He has brain damage! He has brain damage!
这个事实被证实的话他本可以无罪释放的
He could have been acquitted had this fact come out at trial!
他可以被无罪
He could've been acquit--
他可以被无罪释放的
He could've been acquitted.
为什么伯格斯特龙在赦免委员会
Why is Bergstrom even on the Board of Pardons?
他是被州长任命的  都是政治因素
He was appointed by the governor. It's all political.
他是有偏见的  他是党内的反对者
He's biased. He's a party opponent.
我是说  他的办公室其实起诉了塔里克
l mean, his omice practically prosecuted Taliek.
塔里克刚刚被剥夺了宪法赋予他的正当程序的权利
Taliek was just denied his constitutional right to due process.
这就是我们申诉的基础
That is the basis for our appeal.
看起来都不错
It all looks good.
嘿  艾米莉
Hey, Emily.
噢
Oh.
州法庭  地方法院  三号室
State Court, District Court, Third Circuit?
对
Yeah.
- 我马上送过去  - 谢谢
- l'll get them right over there. - Thank you.
- 你去吃早餐吗  - 我上班已经迟到了
- Want to get some breakfast? - l'm already late for work.
谢谢你  尼克
Thank you, Nick.
没事
No problem.
一万一就愿意
l'll go to 11.
约翰  我觉得问题是他们还没有准备好付款
John, l think the problem is they're not prepared to tender any payment.
那交易就取消了
Then the deal's off.
抱歉
Sorry.
我  呃  抱歉
l was, uh... Sorry.
尼克  你和菲尔普斯谈的时候
Nick, when you spoke with Phelps,
有没有感觉他可能会让步
did you get a sense that he might compromise on this?
没有
No.
你再打给他
You'll call him again?
菲尔普斯吗
Phelps?
我认为如果你告诉他我有多认真  他就会
l think if you tell him how serious l am, he'll be--
你是告诉我  你准备放弃从两千四百万
You're telling me that you're willing to walk away
就为了两万二的清理费用吗
from _24 million over a _22,000 clean-up bill?
我只是告诉沃尔特  我愿意出一万一
l just told Walter l'll go to 1 1.
所以你愿意出一万一吗
So you're willing to walk away over 1 1 ,OOO?
对
Yes.
抱歉  约翰  但是  呃
Forgive me, John, but, uh...
是你的公司先污染了土地
lt was your company that contaminated the soil in the first place.
我是说  所有的买家都想你修理它
l mean, all the buyer wants is for you to fix it.
这是原则
lt's the principle.
我们之前一起工作过
We've worked together before.
这不是针对你的原则  这关于一万一千美元  至少要承认这点
lt's not the principle with you. It's about the _1 1 ,OOO. At least admit that.
尼克  看在上帝的份上
Nick, for God's sake.
这是原则  是原则问题
lt is the principle. It is about the principle.
你知道  我
You know, l...
我  我不认为这地方适合我工作
l--l don't think this place is gonna work out for me.
我  抱歉  沃尔特
l'm--l'm sorry, Walter.
- 嘿  - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
我没事了  谢谢
l'm fine now. Thanks a lot.
谢谢
Thank you.
露露  我只是想让你知道我可以做个好爸爸
Lulu, l just want you to know l'm gonna be the best father l can be.
我知道
l know that.
听我说完
Just hear me out.
我猜  呃
l guess, uh...
当你说说你想让她用你的姓氏的时候
When you said you wanted her to have your Iast name,
我意识到了
l realized what that meant.
我觉得你想的太多了  尼克
l think you're reading too much into it, Nick.
不  我不觉得我想多了  露露
No, l don't think l am, Lulu.
你想让孩子用你的姓氏  因为
You want the baby to have your last name because...
因为你不想要我的
because you don't want to have mine.
我说得对吗
Am l right?
露露
Lulu?
对
Yes.
没错
That's right.
我真的很想这么做  尼克
l really wanted to make this work, Nick.
你知道  我
You know, l...
但就是有些事  呃  就是有些事
But there's just something, um, just something--
没事  你不用告诉我
lt's okay. You don't have to tell me.
这就是你的感觉
lt's just how you feel.
对  就是我的感觉
Yeah, it's just how l feel.
没事
lt's okay.
给她你的姓氏
Give her your name.
这不会改变我对她的感觉
lt's not gonna change the way l feel about her.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了  我去看她了
Well, l'm gonna go see her.
尼古拉斯
Nicholas.
爸  过来看你的孙女
Dad. Come and see your granddaughter.
噢  好
Oh, good.
她很漂亮  尼古拉斯
She's beautiful, Nicholas.
你知道  这会
You know, it's gonna be--
会很艰难  我知道  我知道
lt's gonna be hard. l know. l know.
对
Yeah.
她真漂亮
She is beautiful.
是啊
Yeah.
我今天退休了
l stepped down today.
退了律师顾问吗
Of counsel?
对
Yeah.
所以我有很长的时间  陪着她了
So l'm gonna have a lot of time... to be with her.
那很好啊
That'll be great.
我在想如果我们每周日都在一起吃晚饭可能会更好
l was thinking it might be nice if we had Sunday dinner every week.
当然
Sure.
你和我  露露还有她
You and me and Lulu and her.
好
Right.
对  那会很棒的
Yeah, that'll be nice.
什么
What?
怎么了
没事
Nothing.
- 有消息吗  - 不  还没有
- Any news? - No, not yet.
怎么了
What's going on?
我就是在想你可能想去吃点东西
l just thought you might want to go get something to eat.
我在等电话
l gotta wait for the call.
好
Yeah.
你准备好明天的融资会议了吗
You ready for the funding meeting tomorrow?
是的
Yeah.
那
That.
我在想把把这个地方和儿童项目结合起来
Been thinking about merging this place with the Children's Project.
- 凯特·肖的地方吗  - 对
- Kate Shaw's place? - Yeah.
我只剩这些时间了  尼克
l've only got so much time left, Nick.
我的大半辈子都在这里
l've given this place most of my life.
我有事情要做在我  你知道  继续前进
l got things to do before l, you know... move On.
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
嗯  我的手指开始麻木了  有刺痛感
Well, my fingers get numb, tingle.
我有时会摔倒
l fall down sometimes.
对
Yeah.
我知道它要来了
l knew it was coming.
他就是  呃  没那么吓人
lt's just, uh-- It's not as scary.
它只是发生了
That it's happening.
好了  如果你听有消息了  打我电话
Well, if you hear, call me.
安妮
Anne.
是个好名字
lt's a good name.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉
Sorry.
是艾尔文
lt's Alvin.
你好
Hello?
法庭拒绝了我们的请愿书
The courts rejected our petitions.
你还没告诉他吗
Did you tell him yet?
好吧  你应该告诉他了
Well, you should tell him.
他是我最后的案子
He's my last case.
- 你在说什么  - 我是这么想的
- What are you talking about? - l think so.
- 噢  别这样  阿尔文  - 不  不是因为我们输了
- Oh, come on, Alvin. - No, It's not because we lost.
我是时候做些别的事了
lt's time for me to do some other things.
你能替我告诉他吗
Would you tell him for me?
可以  当然
Yeah, sure.
谢谢
Thank you.
你比你想象中的要好
You're a better man than you think you are.
谢谢
Thank you.
记住这点
Remember that.
好的
All right.
- 你没事吧  - 没事
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
抱歉
Sorry.
情绪上来了
Emotional.
没事
All right.
早
Morning.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们还要喝点什么吗
Can l get you anything else to drink?
再来杯咖啡或者水什么的
Another comee or water or something?
不  谢谢
No, thank you.
不用了  谢谢
抱歉  尼克
Excuse me. Nick?
- 你知道阿尔文在哪儿吗  - 他不在这儿吗
- Do you know where Alvin is? - He's not here?
不  他留了这个便条  去南极了
No. He left this note: ''Gone to Antarctica.''
- 很奇怪  不是吗  - 不
- It's weird, isn't it? - No.
好吧  州财政委员会的人在等我
Well, l've got the people from the State Funding Board waiting.
- 好  - 我不知道跟他们说什么
- Right. - l don't know what to say to them.
我很抱歉延迟了
l'm sorry for the delay.
阿尔文是来还是不来
ls Alvin coming or not?
不  阿尔文不来参加这次会议了
No. Alvin won't be coming to this meeting.
不  不  不  别  我在这儿  我可以和你们谈
No, no, no, please. l'm here. l'd like to talk to you.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是尼克·法林
My name's Nick Fallin.
你是这儿的主管吗
Are you in charge here?
对  是的  我是
Yes. Yes, l am.
- 什么时候开始的  - 开始  呃  好吧  我刚上任
- Since when? - Since, uh-- Well, l just started.
你想坐下吗  请吧
Would you like to take a seat, please?
那么  法尔林先生
So, Mr. Fallen?
是法林
Fallin.
法林先生  你需要什么
Mr. Fallin, what are your needs?
钱  很多钱
Money...and a lot of it.
我们有超过五千个客户  如果我们不仔细的话
We have over 5,OOO clients here,and if we're not careful,
他们中的大多数人会走上法律体系的歧途
most of them will wind up on the wrong end of the legal system.
你们中的那些人还不知道
Those of you that don't already know,
匹兹堡法律服务的使命很简单
the mission of Legal Services of Pittsburgh is simple:
为儿童和贫困人民提供
To provide quality legal representation
有质量的合法的法律援助和辩护
and advocacy assistance to children and to the indigent.
我们去年的年度预算超了一百万美金
Our annual budget last year was a little over a million dollars.
我们希望你们今年能至少支付一半的费用
We are hoping that this year you will pay for at least half of that.
联邦预算的削减迫使我们来寻找新的资金来源
Federal budget cuts are forcing us to find new sources of funding.
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177
你们每增加一百美元就能创造一个不同的世界
A 100/o increase on your part would make a world of dimerence.